Before October 7, you published the photo book "Life on the Border".  Which image from it means the most to you today, and why?
There's a picture of five women, mothers, with their own children.
Near the the border,
they're taking them like this.
The eyes
of the children are (looking) inside the kibbutz
and the mothers' looking to the border, to Gaza.
I thought that it's an optimistic photo,
because even though they know that there is Gaza ,
they decided to grow up the children
here in Kfar Aza, near the border.
After October 7, something changed:
Maybe they are looking over there just because
they're afraid of them.
Maybe...
the children are looking inside the kibbutz,
they know that in their generation,
they will have to keep (preserve) it.
And it's a little bit scary,
and it's a little bit a change of mind.
It's the most...
it's the picture that I love more,
more than all the 186 pictures in this book,
but, I'm thinking in another way about it.
So this is my book.